Candace Thurber Stevenson Papers, 1916-1965
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
Candace Thurber Stevenson papers
1916-65
Stevenson, Candace Thurber
MS 155
7 boxes (2.5 linear ft.)
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
Poet and teacher. The papers include manuscripts of poems and stories; correspondence; materials related to writers' conferences and workshops; and Stevenson's book, First the Blade. Correspondence with editors, literary agents, readers, colleagues and friends reveal her personal life and career as a poet and writer.
Candace Thurber was born in Brooklyn, NY in 1883. Her mother supported the family by taking in boarders. She graduated from the Packard Institute, received her A.B. from Smith College in 1904, and her M.A. from Columbia University. After completing her education she taught English in a private school and co-owned a children's bookstore in New York City. In 1912 she married Thomas Kennedy Stevenson, They had one daughter, Caroline. During her adult years Candace Stevenson lived in Missouri, New York City, and Vermont. Many of her poems appeared on the editorial page of the New York Times. She submitted many of her stories to magazines but endured much rejection. She published a collection of her poems, First the Blade, in 1952. Stevenson died July 30, 1968.
The papers include biographical notes, manuscripts of poems and stories, correspondence, materials related to writers' conferences and workshops, and Stevenson's book, First the Blade. Correspondence with editors, literary agents, readers, colleagues and friends reveal her personal life and career as a poet and writer.
This collection is organized into three series:
I. Biographical Materials
II. Conferences and Organizations
III. Writings
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The papers are open to research according to the regulations of the Sophia Smith Collection.
History of the Collection
Candace Thurber Stevenson's papers were donated to the Sophia Smith Collection by her daughter, Caroline Pullman in 1969.
Search Terms
Publishers and publishing--United States--History--Sources; Stevenson, Candace Thurber; Poets, American--20th century--Sources; Women authors, American --20th century--Sources
Additional Information
Related Material
Related material can be found in the Smith College Archives.
- Contents (Box 1, Folder 1)
- SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS
  - Biographical sketch by her daughter, Caroline Pullman, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence
    - Schaffner, John (literary agent) re: Singing Rock, 1953-65 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
    - with publishers in regard to poetry, 1920s-60s (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - with publishers in regard to O'Brien's, Best Short Stories, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - with publishers in regard to poetry, 1916-43, 1952-54 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Contract and royalty reports for First the Blade, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- SERIES II. CONFERENCES AND ORGANIZATIONS
  - Antioch Writer's Conference, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bread Loaf Writer's Conference, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Women Poets (a New York organization to which she belonged), 1956 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Smith College class of 1904 in 1944 (includes correspondence from her class members), 1944 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- SERIES III. WRITINGS
  - Poems
    - A-O by title (printed), undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - A-O (transcripts), undated (Box 3, Folder 2-15)
    - P-Z (printed), undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - P-Z (transcripts), undated (Box 4, Folder 2-8)
    - Harold Vinali poetry class, undated (Box 4, Folder 9-10)
  - Articles and drafts
    - "Baggage and Excess Baggage," undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - "Contest Etiquette," undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - "The County of Westchester," undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - "Four-year Plan for Wilkie Voters" (includes criticisms), 1940 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - "Middle-sized Plan," undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - "More Reflections on the Lazy Thirties," 1927 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - "New Versions of Teaching Posture" (two versions and titles), 1940 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - "Portrait of a School Election," undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - "Two Nuns out of Convents," undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - "We, the Republicans," 1940 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - "Your Money and Your Life" (includes correspondence), 1950 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - "Service Entrance" (first draft, includes criticisms), undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - "Stuyvesant Court" (novel), undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Short stories
    - "Black Magic," undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - "Board Lore," undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - "Borderline," undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - "The Christmas Gift," undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - "The Crystal Ball," undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - "Gateway to the Arena," undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - "Georgette, Debutante," 1927 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - "Good Egg, Bad Egg" (includes criticism), 1920 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - "The Grab Bag," undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - "A Grasshopper Cambol," undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - "Green Light" (two versions and titles), undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - "Heaven Knows Why," undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - "Hyena," undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - "The Invaders" (various versions, includes criticisms), undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - "It Was Algernon," undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - "The Kilmeny Look" (various version, includes criticisms), 1958 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - "A Legacy from Aunt Levinia" (various versions with criticisms), 1929-46 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - "May Day," undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - "Offshore Wind," undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - "Out of the Fog," undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - "The Pewter Teapot," undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - "The Private Life of Corey Ames," undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - "Pumpilia's Broom," 1951-52 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - "The Return," undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - "Shades of Sherwood," 1961 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - "A Sign for Miss Kitty," undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - "The Singing Rock," undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - "Spring Again," undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - "Spring Holiday," undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - "Sugar Loaf Scannel," undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - "Top Secret," undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - "Tranquil Souls," undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - "Vendetta," undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - First The Blade
    - Typescript, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Proof sheets, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Book jackets, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Publicity, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Financial statements and correspondence with publisher, E.P. Dutton, 1952-55 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with publishers other than Dutton, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Permission to reprint already published poems, 1949-50 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Reviews of First the Blade and correspondence about reviews, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Congratulatory notes, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 9)